<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tags on Elizabeth Malara</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/</link><description>Recent content in Tags on Elizabeth Malara</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://malara.ca/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Awards</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/awards/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/awards/</guid><description>I am proud to present you paintings which won prizes and distinctions during juried events.</description></item><item><title>Drawing</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/drawing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/drawing/</guid><description>Drawing evolved from a sketch into an illustration and gives me more and more independent form of expression to allow me to search the means for not only a record of impressions and observations, but also to capture the emotions and thoughts of the heroes of my drawings.</description></item><item><title>Watercolor</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/watercolor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/watercolor/</guid><description>Watercolor allows me to immerse myself completely in the painting, because it requires the totally undivided attention to combine the randomness of the game of flowing hue and tint with a perfect grasp of unique paint effects that are melted on the virgin paper.</description></item><item><title>Acrylic</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/acrylic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/acrylic/</guid><description>Acrylic is an instant and rapid technique for me, giving a wonderful texture, which will produce so many different results. In my paintings I&amp;rsquo;m fascinated by the similarity of acrylic texture to the embroidery, where I am weaving the matter of painting, weaving colors.</description></item><item><title>Oil</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/oil/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/oil/</guid><description>Oil technique is my first love and a safe haven of trusted technique. I like the job with a pallet knife and a dynamic brush stroke and trail. The oil is suitable for both quick and spontaneous work as well as longer contemplation and searching for harmony in the image.</description></item><item><title>Still Life</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/stilllife/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/stilllife/</guid><description>Still life is for me a kind of exercise and at the same time an exam, how I find a color, how I analyze and solve a topic and composition. This is a testing ground for me, especially since my interest in acrylic technique. I paint until the still life begins to live its own life.</description></item><item><title>Landscape</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/landscape/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/landscape/</guid><description>Nature is the greatest inspiration for me. I really value outdoor painting. Out of necessity, the paintings are continued and finished in the studio, but I cherish capturing original inspiration resulting from direct contact with constant changes of plain air observations.</description></item><item><title>Portrait</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/portrait/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/portrait/</guid><description>Portraits are my favorite themes, but I do them rarely, mainly for my friends or as commissioned pictures. It is a special time spent with my model and the specific atmosphere that impressed me deeply. And I am happy when this extra vibe is visible in the works.</description></item><item><title>embroidery</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/embroidery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/embroidery/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/featured/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/featured/</guid><description>Admiration of the beauty that surrounds me gives meaning to my life and action. I have experienced this feeling since I was young and I can gladly say that over the years, it is still blooming in me. As an artist, I try to transfer onto canvas, by means of colors and textures, brush, palette knife, pen or pencil all that fascinates me. Nature is my inspiration; whether it be the changing seasons, still life or portraits.</description></item><item><title>ontario</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/ontario/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/ontario/</guid><description/></item><item><title>tobermory</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/tobermory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/tobermory/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Archive</title><link>https://malara.ca/tags/archive/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://malara.ca/tags/archive/</guid><description>A collection of my works from 1988 to 2008, the period of academic and post-academic studies. Most of the works are done upon nature observation, as well as a few copies made in museums. There are also embroidery and painting compositions, showing my inclinations toward symbolic themes.</description></item></channel></rss>